KIRILL RYZHOV

London, UK | +44 777 6154072 | kryzhov@zoho.eu | linkedin.com/in/kryzhov/

CAREER OBJECTIVE -

Financial Analyst specialising in financial modelling, data and predictive analytics, quantitative analysis, and financial risk management. Has commercial experience in strategy, market analysis and business development.

Delivered consultancy and technical advisory assignments within Energy, Power and Utilities practice, including asset management, operations, technology review, and technical due diligence.

Project management supporting delivery of power infrastructure projects with up to £50M in value across UK, Europe, SE Asia, and Middle East, working collaboratively with multi-disciplinary teams and key project stakeholders.

Strong academic background encompassing MSc in Power Systems Engineering, MSc Financial Risk and Investment Analysis (Distinction) and working towards Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) qualification.

CORE COMPETENCIES :

Power | Energy | Infrastructure | Energy Commodities | Consulting | Strategy | Financial and Technical Advisory Project Management | Cross-Functional Collaboration | Business Development | Client and Stakeholder Management Design and Engineering | Data Analysis | Predictive analytics | Russian Language | Python, SQL, NoSQL, Tableau, VBA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE -

Self-Employed

Financial Consultant 2017-2018

- Qualitative research for developments in Battery Energy Storage Solutions. Comparative analysis of valuation approaches, specifically focusing on synergy from co-locations with renewable energy generation.
- Support for backend development of the financial risks management software, specifying approach to risk modelling, contributing risk model library, descriptive analytics on performance measurement and attribution.

Mott MacDonald

Lead Chartered Engineer, Project Manager

2011-2016

- Delivered expert technical counsel to power utilities and financial intermediaries, including review of strategy, technology, operations, technical advisory and due diligence.
- Executed full lifecycle of power infrastructure projects, including conceptual studies, planning, development consent orders, designs, specifications, regulatory compliance, EPC tendering, testing and procurement.
- Directed strategy planning and operational decision-making through comprehensive technical analysis, amplified by quantified risk assessments and forming a regulatory framework, cutting operational cost by 18%.
- Provided leadership and coordination to cross-functional teams for multi-disciplinary projects worldwide.
- Scripted competitive high value bids and proposals, taking responsibility for team building, concepts and practical delivery methods, project execution schedules, contracts structuring, and client negotiations.
- Increased team revenues by 30% through successful business development initiative, spanning strategic analysis, sourcing and valuation of new business opportunities.

3M

Engineer

2008-2011

- External consultant and technical advisory for Power and Utilities sector in Russia, CIS, and EE region.
- Delivered range of innovative power infrastructure projects through concept development, design, supply and delivery, construction supervision, and commissioning.
- Elevated overall quality of product support (portfolio of 20 applications) through development of all-round approach, from business development, marketing, regulatory and governance to cultivation of collaborative relationships with major stakeholders, designers and utilities.
- Trained and developed external teams through presentations, workshops and hands-on trainings, introducing industry's best practises, innovative products and approaches to engineering and construction.

EDUCATION -

Udacity

Data Scientist and Machine Learning Nanodegrees

2017-2018

University of Sussex

MSc Financial Risk and Investment Analysis with Distinction

2016-2017

- Finance, statistics, financial modelling, alternative investment analysis, and risk management.
- Developed valuation models for renewable power plants and commodities supply contracts, encompassing multi-level stochastic forecasting, risk-based hedging with forwards and options, real option pricing, and transaction structuring including equity and debt structuring with conventional and participatory bonds.
- Created and analysed market risk models for various portfolios, included data optimisation and management, risk factor mapping, out-of-sample diagnostic, scenario and factor push stress-tests. Risk Mitigation Strategies.

Moscow Power Engineering University